In this video, we're going to wrap up our discussion of SLR parsing, we're going to
在这段视频中，我们将结束对单反解析的讨论，我们将
give the full SLR parsing algorithm, and also talk about some important
给出了完整的SLR解析算法，并讨论了一些重要的问题
improvements. The SLR parsing algorithm we discussed in the last video has one major
改进。我们在上一段视频中讨论的SLR解析算法有一个主要特点
inefficiency. And that is that most of the work that the automation does when it,
效率低下。这就是自动化所做的大部分工作，当它，
when it reads the stack is actually redundant. And to see this, think about
当它读取时，堆栈实际上是冗余的。要看到这一点，请想一想
the stack. So we have our stack, and this is the bottom over here. And this is the
堆栈。所以我们有我们的堆栈，这是这里的底部。这就是
top of the stack over here. And, what is going on in each step? In each step we
堆栈的顶部在这里。那么，每一步都在做些什么呢？在每一步我们
might, shift something onto the stacks, we might add one symbol, or we might pop some
可能会将一些东西移到堆栈上，我们可能会添加一个符号，或者我们可能会弹出一些符号
symbols, and, and push one symbol onto the stack. But basically there's going to be
符号，和，并将一个符号压入堆栈。但基本上会有
some small number of symbols that change at the top of the stack at each step. But
在每个步骤中在堆栈顶部更改的一些少量符号。但
most of the stack stays the same. And then we rerun the automaton on the entire
堆栈的大部分保持不变。然后我们重新运行整个自动机
stack. And so, this work is all repeated. Everything that stayed the same From the
堆栈。因此，这些工作都是重复的。所有保持不变的东西都是从
previous stack is repeated work, and then we do a little bit of new work, just at
前面的堆栈是重复的工作，然后我们做一些新的工作，就在
the very top of the stack. And clearly, if we could avoid this, we could make the
堆栈的最顶端。很明显，如果我们能避免这种情况，我们就可以
algorithm run much, much more quickly. The way to exploit the observation that most
算法的运行速度要快得多。利用观察到的最重要的
of the work of the automaton is repeated at each step, is to simply remember the
自动机的工作在每一步都是重复的，就是简单地记住
state of the automaton on each stack prefix. So we're going to change the
每个堆栈前缀上的自动机的状态。所以我们要改变
representation of the stack, we're going to change what goes in the stack, so
表示，我们将更改堆栈中的内容，因此
before we just had symbols on the stack, but now we're going to have pairs. Each
以前我们只有堆栈上的符号，但现在我们将有对。每个人
element of the stack will be a pair of a symbol, and a DFA state. Thus the stack
堆栈的元素将是一对符号和DFA状态。因此，堆栈
now is going to be a stack of pairs and whereas before a stack would have
现在将是一堆对，而在堆栈之前
consisted just of the symbols, sym1 up to sym n, now we're going to have the same
仅由符号组成，sym1到sym，现在我们将有相同的
symbols but each one of them is going to be paired with a DFA state and that DFA
符号，但每个符号都将与DFA状态和该DFA配对
state is going to be the result of running the DFA and all the symbols to its left,
状态将是运行DFA及其左侧的所有符号的结果，
So all the symbols below it in the stack. So if I think about my stack and if I draw
所以堆栈中它下面的所有符号。所以如果我考虑我的堆栈，如果我画
a little picture of the stack as a line then the DFA state here. Let's call this
堆栈的一小张图片是一条线，然后是DFA状态。让我们把这个叫做
state I, will be the result of running the DFA on the entire, stack contents to the
状态i将是在整个堆栈内容上运行DFA到
left of that point. And again, if I look at some other point in the stack, at the
在那个点的左边。再一次，如果我看一下堆栈中的其他点，在
state, stack state that's stored there. That would be running, the results of
状态，存储在那里的堆栈状态。那就是运行，结果是
running the DFA on the entire stack context, contents, up to that point. And
在此之前，在整个堆栈上下文、内容上运行DFA。和
one small detail here is that the bottom of the stack, we have to get started. We
这里的一个小细节是堆栈的底部，我们必须开始。我们
need to have the start state stored at the bottom of the stack. And we just store
需要将开始状态存储在堆栈的底部。我们只是储存
that with any dummy symbol. It doesn't matter what symbol we pick. So now we're
任何虚拟符号。我们选什么符号并不重要。所以现在我们是
ready to actually give the details of the parsing algorithm. And the first step is
准备好实际给出解析算法的细节。第一步是
to define a table go to. And this maps a state and a symbol to another state. And
要定义表格，请转到。这将一个状态和一个符号映射到另一个状态。和
this is just the transition function of the DFA. This is the graph of the DFA
这只是DFA的过渡函数。这是DFA的图表
written out as an array. Our SLR parsing algorithm will have four possible moves. A
以数组形式写出。我们的SLR解析算法将有四个可能的步骤。一个
shift X move will push a pair on the stack. X is a DFA state, so that's named
Shift X移动将在堆栈上推送对。X是DFA状态，所以它被命名为
in the shift move now. And then the other element of the pair is the current input.
现在就在换班行动中。然后，该对中的另一个元素是电流输入。
And then we'll also have reduce moves, which are just as before. So, to recall, a
然后我们还会有减少动作，就像以前一样。所以，回想一下，一个
reduce move will pop, the, a number of elements from the stack equal to the
Reduce Move将从堆栈中弹出等于
length of the right hand side. And then it will push the left hand side onto the
右手边的长度。然后它会把左手边推到
stack. And then finally, accept an error moves for when we've successfully parsed
堆栈。最后，当我们成功解析时，接受错误移动
the input, and for when the parser gets stuck. The second parsing table is the
输入，以及解析器被卡住时使用。第二个解析表是
action table which tells us which kind of move to make in every possible state. The
动作表，它告诉我们在每种可能的状态下应该做哪种动作。这个
action table's indexed by a state of the automaton and the next input symbol. And
动作表由自动机的状态和下一个输入符号索引。和
then the possible moves are things like shift, reduce, accept, or error. So let's
然后可能的动作是移位、减少、接受或错误。所以让我们
consider if we do shifts, if the final state of the automaton at the top of the
考虑一下，如果我们做移位，如果自动机在顶部的最终状态
stack has an item that says it would be okay to shift an A. And go to that is from
Stack有一个项，它说可以将A移位，然后转到它是从
this state we can go to state J on input A. Then the move in state I on input A
这个状态我们可以在输入A上转到状态J，然后在输入A上的状态I中的移动
will be to shift AJ onto the stack And th ink about what that means for a second.
就是将AJ移到堆栈上，然后思考一下这意味着什么。
What that says is that we have a stack. And then the next input is A. And then at
这就是说我们有一个堆栈。然后下一个输入是A，然后在
this point, it's okay to shift an A onto the stack. And furthermore, that the state
在这一点上，将A移到堆栈上是可以的。此外，州政府
of the automaton at this point is SI. Okay. So the state of Irarta [inaudible]
在这一点上，自动机的大小是SI。好吧。所以伊拉尔塔的状态[听不见]
the top of the stack is SI. The next input is A. Remember that the go to table is a
堆栈的顶部是SI。下一个输入是a。请记住，转到表是一个
transition function of the machine. So if we move the vertical bar over, if we shift
机器的过渡功能。所以如果我们把竖条移过去，如果我们移动
that A on to the stack, well, now, we don't just put A on the stack, we have to
把A放到堆栈上，现在，我们不只是把A放到堆栈上，我们必须
put a pair on the stack. And the question is what machine state should go there.
把一对放到堆栈上。问题是机器的状态应该是什么。
Well, it's going to be state that we would reach from state I from state SI on input
好，这将是状态，我们将从状态I在输入上从状态SI到达
A, which. The go to table tells us, in this case, is state SJ. And for that
A，哪一个。转到表告诉我们，在这种情况下，是状态Sj。为此，
reason, the action, when we terminate in state I, and the next input is A, is to
原因是，当我们在状态I终止，并且下一个输入是A时，动作是
shift the pair A, J, onto the stack. The other three moves that go into the action
将A，J对移到堆栈上。进入行动的另外三个动作
table are things we've already seen. So if the final state of the automaton at the
桌子是我们已经看过的东西。所以如果自动机的最终状态在
top of the stack has an item that says that we can reduce, and the follow up
堆栈的顶部有一个项目，上面说我们可以减少，后续的
condition requirement is satisfied. Mainly, that the, next input can follow,
满足条件要求。主要是，下一个输入可以跟在后面，
the left hand side non terminal of the production. Then in the entry I, for,
产品的左侧非终端。那么在条目I，for，
[inaudible] if we're in state SI and we have input a, we can reduce by the
[听不见]如果我们处于状态SI并且我们有输入a，我们可以减去
production x goes to alpha. And there's one exception here, we're not going to do
x的乘积是α。这里有一个例外，我们不会
that reduction, if the left-hand side is the special start symbol, the new start
如果左侧是特殊的开始符号，则新的开始
symbol that we add to the grammar, is prime. Because, in that case, if the item
我们添加到语法中的符号是质数。因为，在这种情况下，如果物品
that we're going to reduce by is s-prime goes to s-dot, and we're at the end of the
我们要减去的是s-质数是s-点，我们在
input, then we want to accept. And any other Situation is an error. So in any
输入，那么我们就想接受。任何其他情况都是错误的。所以在任何情况下
other situation, if we're in state I and we have the next the next input is A,
其他情况，如果我们在状态I，我们有下一个，下一个输入是A，
well, we don't know whether to shift, reduce, or accept. And so, that is an
嗯，我们不知道是转移、减少还是接受。所以，这是一个
error state. Finally, here is the full SLR parsing algorithm. And I'm just going to
错误状态。最后，这里是完整的SLR解析算法。我只是要去
walk you through it, so that we can see how all of the ideas we've been di
向你介绍一下，这样我们就能看到我们所有的想法是如何
scussing, and all the various pieces fit together. Let's let our initial input be
冲刺，所有不同的部件都拼凑在一起。让我们将初始输入设为
called I. And we'll just give it a name, and it's gonna be treated as an array that
称为I。，我们只给它一个名称，它将被当作一个数组来处理，该数组
we can index. The index will be called J, and initially, it's zero so that we're
我们可以编索引。索引将被命名为J，最初，它是零，所以我们是
pointing to the first token in the input string. We'll just assume that the first
指向输入字符串中的第一个标记。我们就假设第一个
state of the DFA is called state one. And, that means our initial stack is going to
DFA的状态称为状态一。这意味着我们的初始堆栈将
have state one for the state of the automaton and some other dummy symbol that
具有表示自动机状态的状态1和一些其他虚拟符号，该符号
we don't care about In the, in the first position. So, the stack is just a pair
我们不关心在，在第一个位置。所以，堆栈只是一对
with [inaudible] in the start state of the DFA. And now, were going to repeat the
在DFA的开始状态下[听不到]。现在，我们要重复
following loop until we've either successfully pars the input or we detect
跟随循环，直到我们成功解析输入或检测到
an error. And at its steps, what we're going to do? Well, we're going to look at
一个错误。在它的台阶上，我们要做什么呢？好的，我们接下来要看的是
the next input symbol and we're going to look at the final state of the automaton
下一个输入符号，我们将查看自动机的最终状态
on the stack contents and that's always the state of the pair that's on the top of
在堆栈内容上，而这始终是位于堆栈内容顶部的对的状态
the stack and we're gonna look those two things up in the action table and that's
堆栈，我们要在动作表中查找这两件事，那就是
gonna tell us what kind of move to make. So, let's just go through the moves in
会告诉我们该采取什么样的行动。所以，让我们先来看一下
order. Let's consider the shift move first. So, what happens? If were, if it
请遵守秩序。让我们先考虑一下换班动作。那么，会发生什么呢？如果是的话，如果是这样的话
says we're supposed to shift and going to state K, then what we're going to do is
说我们应该转移到K州，然后我们要做的是
we're going to shift the input, that means we're going to take the next input symbol
我们将移位输入，这意味着我们将采用下一个输入符号
and, or the current input symbol, excuse me, and we're going to push that on to the
或者当前的输入符号，打扰一下，我们要把它推到
stack together with state K of the [inaudible]. That pair goes on to the
与[听不见]的状态K堆叠在一起。那两个人继续前往
stack, and we also bumb the input pointer so that we're looking at the next
堆栈，并且我们还增加了输入指针，因此我们将查看下一个
character of input. Now. Let me erase that so you can continue to read it. Now what
输入的字符。现在。让我把它擦掉，这样你就可以继续读了。现在怎么办？
about the reduce moves? So this one's a little bit interesting. First thing we're
关于减少行动的事吗？所以这个有点有趣。我们首先要做的是
going to do is we're going to pop a number of pairs off the, off the stack that's
接下来要做的是，我们将从堆栈中弹出一些配对，也就是
equal to the length of the right-hand side. So we pop a number of items off the
等于右手边的长度。所以我们从
stack that's going to the right that's equal to the right-hand side of the
向右的堆栈，该堆栈等于
production, and then what do w e push on to the stack? Well we're gonna push the
生产，然后我们向堆栈推送什么？好的，我们要把
non-terminal on the left-hand side of the stack. And now the question is: what state
堆栈左侧的非终端。现在的问题是：什么样的州
goes on to the stack? What DFA state? Well. With that we've popped the stack. We
会进入堆栈吗？什么DFA状态？井。这样，我们就可以弹出堆栈了。我们
can look at the new top state of the stack. So the DFA state was now the top
可以查看堆栈的新顶部状态。因此，DFA状态现在是最重要的
state. After we've done the pops we'll tell us what the final state of the DFA
州政府。在我们完成POP之后，我们将告诉我们DFA的最终状态是什么
was and what is left of the stack. And then now that we're pushing X under the
堆栈的过去和剩余部分。现在我们把X推到
stack we want to know what state the DFA would go into on the transition labeled X.
堆栈，我们想知道DFA在标记为X的转换上会进入什么状态。
And so we use the Go To table to look that up, The current top state of the stack. On
因此，我们使用转到表来查找堆栈的当前顶部状态。在……上面
symbol X, where does the FA go? That is the state that gets pushed onto the stack.
符号X，英足总的去向是什么？这是推送到堆栈上的状态。
And then finally, if, if the move is accept, we halt normally. And if the move
最后，如果移动被接受，我们就会正常停止。如果搬家
is error, we halt and report an error, or execute our error recovery procedure. One
如果出现错误，我们会暂停并报告错误，或者执行错误恢复过程。一
interesting fact about this algorithm is that it only uses the DFA state and the
关于此算法的有趣事实是，它只使用DFA状态和
input. The stack symbols are not used in really interesting way. And so, we could
输入。堆栈符号并没有以真正有趣的方式使用。所以，我们可以
actually get rid of the stack symbols and just do parsings with the DFA states on
实际上去掉了堆栈符号，只需在打开DFA状态的情况下进行解析
the stack. But, that of course would be throwing away the program and we still
堆栈。但是，这当然会抛弃这个项目，而我们仍然
actually need to program for the later stages of the compiler. And so to do the
实际上需要为编译器的后期阶段进行编程。因此，要做到这一点，
type checking and co-generation, we need to keep the symbols around. Now simple LR
类型检查和联合生成，我们需要保留符号。现在简单的LR
parsing is called simple for a reason. And in fact, in practice, it's a bit too
将解析称为简单是有原因的。事实上，在实践中，它也有一点
simple. The widely used bottom-up parsing algorithms are based on a more powerful
很简单。广泛使用的自底向上解析算法是基于功能更强大的
class of grammars called the LR grammars. And the basic difference between the LR
一类称为LR文法的文法。以及LR和LR之间的基本区别
grammars and the SLR grammars is that look ahead is built into the items. So what
语法和单反语法是，向前看是内置在项目中的。那又怎样
does that mean? Well, a LR1 item is going to be a pair which consists of an item,
那是不是意味着？嗯，一个LR1项目将是由一个项目组成的一对，
Just like we saw before. And this means exactly the same thing as before. And a
就像我们之前看到的一样。这和以前的意思完全一样。和一个
look-ahead, In case of an LR1 item there's just one token of look-ahead. If this was
前瞻，在LR1物品的情况下，只有一个前瞻的标志。如果这是
an LR2 item there could be two tokens of look-ahead in there. And the meaning of
一个LR2物品，里面可能有两个前瞻的记号。以及它的意义
this pair is that, if we ever get aroun d to state where we have seen all of this
这两个是，如果我们有机会说出我们在哪里看到了这一切
production, all the right-hand side of this production. Then it's going to be
生产，这部产品的右手边。那就会是
okay to reduce, if the look-ahead at that point is Dollar that's the end of the
可以减持，如果在这一点上向前看是美元，那么就结束了
input. And of course, there could be any other token in there any other terminal
输入。当然，那里可能有任何其他令牌，任何其他终端
symbol in there besides dollar. And this turns out to be more accurate than just
除了美元，还有符号。事实证明，这比仅仅
using follow sense recall that the point where a reduction decision is made in SLR
使用Follow Sense回想在SLR中做出减少决定的点
parsing, we just look at the entire follow set for the symbol on the left hand side
解析时，我们只需查看左侧符号的整个跟随集
of the production. And this mechanism of encoding the look-ahead in to the items
这部作品的主人公。这种对项目的超前处理进行编码的机制
allow us to track and find the [inaudible] which look-aheads are actually possible in
允许我们追踪并找到[听不见的]那些看起来实际上是可能的
particular production sequences. And if you look at the automaton for your parser,
特定的生产序列。如果你看一下解析器的自动机，
actually it's not an LR1 automaton. It's an LALR1 automaton, which is something
实际上它不是LR1自动机。这是一个LALR1自动机，这是一种
very close, to an LR automaton, it's a little bit of an optimization over an LR,
非常接近LR自动机，与LR相比有点优化，
a pure LR automaton, but anyway, it uses exactly the same kinds of items with this
一个纯LR自动机，但不管怎样，它使用的项目种类与这个完全相同
pair of a of a standard LR0 item in a look ahead. If you look at that automaton, you
前瞻中的一对标准LR0物品。如果你看看那个机器人，你会发现
will see items that look like this, and that will help you in reading the
将看到如下所示的项目，这将帮助您阅读
automaton and figuring out what it is doing.
并弄清楚它在做什么。